<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hazard</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hazard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 23:50:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Level_2</title>
      <link>/post/level_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 23:50:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/level_2/</guid>
      <description>Level 2 Hi World, how are you doing today?? So this is going to be the Level 2 of the ReversingHero Writeup. Once again thanks to xorpd for creating such wonderful executable and giving me permission to write about it.
Lets jump right into it.
 As you saw in previous post, we get a new folder named &amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; after completing level_1.
Here we see the same configuration one p and one x file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level_1</title>
      <link>/post/level_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 15:45:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/level_1/</guid>
      <description>Reversing Hero Level 1 Introduction  So today I decided to write a small writeup on Level 1 of ReversingHero Challenge. This is a pretty easy Level as it is the first. But the difficulty will increase advancing further Levels. While learning RE in my 3rd year of college, I came across a thread on reddit which was addressed to RE newbies to give some learning Resources. I then found out about ReversingHero challenge there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Formatted Disk</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 22:50:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes there are some decisions you make and erase your whole Partition of a Hard Drive. This happens usually when you are installing a new OS in your system. This is a problem that many face during their learning period in IT courses. I similarly have faced this issue about 4-5 times and this things create a great havoc. When google to recover the data I have lost, there are software Packages but you have to pay to use their services.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
